[
  {
    "id": 1301,
    "question": "compañero",
    "questionDetails": "Era mi compañero en el furgón.",
    "answer": "partner",
    "answerDetails": "He was my partner in the truck."
  },
  {
    "id": 1302,
    "question": "nuevas",
    "answer": "New"
  },
  {
    "id": 1303,
    "question": "dormido",
    "questionDetails": "Pronto se quedó dormido.",
    "answer": "asleep",
    "answerDetails": "He soon fell asleep."
  },
  {
    "id": 1304,
    "question": "llevaba",
    "questionDetails": "Ella llevaba un vestido de diseñador cuando le tomaron la foto.",
    "answer": "she wore, he carried, i was wearing",
    "answerDetails": "She wore a designer gown when they took her picture."
  },
  {
    "id": 1305,
    "question": "sube",
    "answer": "he puts on"
  },
  {
    "id": 1306,
    "question": "segundos",
    "questionDetails": "Hace dos segundos estaba relajado.",
    "answer": "seconds, sec",
    "answerDetails": "I was relaxed about two seconds ago."
  },
  {
    "id": 1307,
    "question": "ventana",
    "questionDetails": "Acércate a la ventana y mírame.",
    "answer": "window",
    "answerDetails": "Go to the window and look at me."
  },
  {
    "id": 1308,
    "question": "pa",
    "questionDetails": "Todo porque pa te convenció.",
    "answer": "pa, AP, BP",
    "answerDetails": "Everything because pa convinced you."
  },
  {
    "id": 1309,
    "question": "espere",
    "answer": "Wait"
  },
  {
    "id": 1310,
    "question": "oficial",
    "questionDetails": "Los miembros sabrían cuando la acción industrial es oficial.",
    "answer": "official, officer",
    "answerDetails": "Members would know when industrial action is official."
  },
  {
    "id": 1311,
    "question": "embarazada",
    "questionDetails": "Yo ya estaba embarazada cuando salió de la cárcel.",
    "answer": "pregnant",
    "answerDetails": "I was already pregnant when he got out of prison."
  },
  {
    "id": 1312,
    "question": "acaso",
    "questionDetails": "Señora, acaso vernos os ha sorprendido.",
    "answer": "perhaps",
    "answerDetails": "Perhaps madame is surprised to see us!"
  },
  {
    "id": 1313,
    "question": "cenar",
    "questionDetails": "Cenaron pavo, relleno y verduras asadas en su festín del Día de Acción de Gracias.",
    "answer": "dine, eat dinner",
    "answerDetails": "They dined on turkey, stuffing, and roasted vegetables for their Thanksgiving feast."
  },
  {
    "id": 1314,
    "question": "exacto",
    "questionDetails": "Los detalles exactos todavía estaban siendo elaborado.",
    "answer": "exact",
    "answerDetails": "The exact details were still being worked out."
  },
  {
    "id": 1315,
    "question": "contento",
    "questionDetails": "Estoy contento de saber que al final perdonaste a tu hermano.",
    "answer": "glad, satisfied",
    "answerDetails": "I’m glad to know that in the end you forgave your brother."
  },
  {
    "id": 1316,
    "question": "salgo",
    "questionDetails": "… una buena idea que salgo con gente de mi edad.",
    "answer": "hang out, out",
    "answerDetails": "… a good idea to hang out with people my own age."
  },
  {
    "id": 1317,
    "question": "depende",
    "answer": "Depends on"
  },
  {
    "id": 1318,
    "question": "escuchando",
    "questionDetails": "Mi espada está escuchando.",
    "answer": "listening, hearing, Iistening",
    "answerDetails": "My sword is listening."
  },
  {
    "id": 1319,
    "question": "interesante",
    "questionDetails": "Será muy interesante ver lo que vienen con.",
    "answer": "interesting",
    "answerDetails": "It will be very interesting to see what they come up with."
  },
  {
    "id": 1320,
    "question": "toques",
    "questionDetails": "Vete a la parte de atrás y no toques nada.",
    "answer": "touch, hints, curfews",
    "answerDetails": "Get in the back and don’t touch anything."
  },
  {
    "id": 1321,
    "question": "obra",
    "questionDetails": "La obra de arte en la chaqueta de polvo se repite en la cubierta.",
    "answer": "artwork, construction, building site",
    "answerDetails": "The artwork on the dust jacket is repeated on the cover."
  },
  {
    "id": 1322,
    "question": "deseo",
    "questionDetails": "Que se aferraban juntos en el deseo feroz.",
    "answer": "desire",
    "answerDetails": "They were clinging together in fierce desire."
  },
  {
    "id": 1323,
    "question": "ocurra",
    "questionDetails": "Que esto les ocurra a dos miembros del equipo.",
    "answer": "happen, occur, dare",
    "answerDetails": "For this to happen to two members of the team."
  },
  {
    "id": 1324,
    "question": "sal",
    "questionDetails": "Sales de baño.",
    "answer": "salt",
    "answerDetails": "(bath) salts."
  },
  {
    "id": 1325,
    "question": "piernas",
    "questionDetails": "Y tengo las piernas lo bastante largas.",
    "answer": "legs, Iegs, lap",
    "answerDetails": "And my legs are quite long enough."
  },
  {
    "id": 1326,
    "question": "uh",
    "questionDetails": "Tengo se, uh, se declaración aquí mismo.",
    "answer": "uh",
    "answerDetails": "I have her, uh, statement right here."
  },
  {
    "id": 1327,
    "question": "malas",
    "questionDetails": "Las películas fueron malas.",
    "answer": "bad, evil, poor",
    "answerDetails": "The movies were bad."
  },
  {
    "id": 1328,
    "question": "modo",
    "questionDetails": "No lo vemos de ese modo.",
    "answer": "way",
    "answerDetails": "We do not see it that way."
  },
  {
    "id": 1329,
    "question": "olvidar",
    "questionDetails": "Puedes olvidar tu viaje al parque de atracciones.",
    "answer": "forget",
    "answerDetails": "You can forget your trip to the amusement park."
  },
  {
    "id": 1330,
    "question": "solución",
    "questionDetails": "¿Cómo llegaste a la solución del problema?",
    "answer": "solution",
    "answerDetails": "How did you arrive at the solution to the problem?"
  },
  {
    "id": 1331,
    "question": "mover",
    "questionDetails": "Los libreros deben poder fácilmente mover esta biografía de Lincoln.",
    "answer": "move, wiggle",
    "answerDetails": "Booksellers should easily be able to move this biography of Lincoln."
  },
  {
    "id": 1332,
    "question": "santo",
    "questionDetails": "Ven en nuestra presencia como testigo de este santo matrimonio.",
    "answer": "holy",
    "answerDetails": "Come into our presence and witness this holy matrimony."
  },
  {
    "id": 1333,
    "question": "vieron",
    "questionDetails": "¿Qué hicieron anoche?-Vieron una película.",
    "answer": "they watched",
    "answerDetails": "What did they do last night?-They watched a movie."
  },
  {
    "id": 1334,
    "question": "oído",
    "questionDetails": "Les entra por un oído y sale por el otro.",
    "answer": "ear",
    "answerDetails": "In one ear and out the other."
  },
  {
    "id": 1335,
    "question": "intención",
    "questionDetails": "Negó el incendio intencional con la intención de poner en peligro la vida.",
    "answer": "intent",
    "answerDetails": "He denied arson with intent to endanger life."
  },
  {
    "id": 1336,
    "question": "diferentes",
    "questionDetails": "El proletariado pasa por diferentes etapas de desarrollo.",
    "answer": "various",
    "answerDetails": "The proletariat goes through various stages of development."
  },
  {
    "id": 1337,
    "question": "posición",
    "questionDetails": "Dejó muy clara su posición al comienzo del debate.",
    "answer": "position, setting",
    "answerDetails": "He made his position very clear at the beginning of the debate."
  },
  {
    "id": 1338,
    "question": "estuvimos",
    "questionDetails": "Nunca sabrán que estuvimos aquí.",
    "answer": "were, stayed",
    "answerDetails": "Hunters will never know we were here."
  },
  {
    "id": 1339,
    "question": "enseguida",
    "questionDetails": "Si me mandas un email por la mañana, te responderé enseguida.",
    "answer": "straightaway, presently",
    "answerDetails": "If you send me an email in the morning, I’ll respond straightaway."
  },
  {
    "id": 1340,
    "question": "interior",
    "questionDetails": "Limpie el interior del parabrisas.",
    "answer": "inside, inner, internal",
    "answerDetails": "Wipe the inside of the windscreen."
  },
  {
    "id": 1341,
    "question": "agradezco",
    "answer": "i am grateful"
  },
  {
    "id": 1342,
    "question": "traes",
    "questionDetails": "Si me traes su cabeza.",
    "answer": "bring",
    "answerDetails": "Bring me his head."
  },
  {
    "id": 1343,
    "question": "director",
    "questionDetails": "El director del estudio.",
    "answer": "head",
    "answerDetails": "The head of the whole studio."
  },
  {
    "id": 1344,
    "question": "obviamente",
    "questionDetails": "Ella era, obviamente, poco bien.",
    "answer": "obviously",
    "answerDetails": "She was obviously unwell."
  },
  {
    "id": 1345,
    "question": "esperanza",
    "questionDetails": "Tener (Grandes) esperanzas de hacer algo.",
    "answer": "hope, expectation",
    "answerDetails": "To have (high) hopes of doing something."
  },
  {
    "id": 1346,
    "question": "culpable",
    "questionDetails": "Ella era culpable de un grave error de juicio.",
    "answer": "guilty",
    "answerDetails": "She was guilty of a serious error of judgement."
  },
  {
    "id": 1347,
    "question": "sepas",
    "questionDetails": "Realmente no creo que sepas.",
    "answer": "know",
    "answerDetails": "I really don’t think you know."
  },
  {
    "id": 1348,
    "question": "inteligente",
    "questionDetails": "Ella era una mujer joven muy inteligente y estudioso.",
    "answer": "clever",
    "answerDetails": "She was an extremely clever and studious young woman."
  },
  {
    "id": 1349,
    "question": "hermoso",
    "questionDetails": "Habló en inglés hermoso.",
    "answer": "beautiful, lovely, gorgeous",
    "answerDetails": "She spoke in beautiful English."
  },
  {
    "id": 1350,
    "question": "responsabilidad",
    "questionDetails": "El parque de atracciones no asume responsabilidad por objetos perdidos en las atracciones.",
    "answer": "liability",
    "answerDetails": "The amusement park does not accept liability for any objects lost on the rides."
  },
  {
    "id": 1351,
    "question": "permite",
    "questionDetails": "Permite que los padres reduzcan sus ingresos gravables mientras ahorran para la educación universitaria de su hijo.",
    "answer": "it allows",
    "answerDetails": "It allows parents to reduce their taxable income while saving for their child’s college education."
  },
  {
    "id": 1352,
    "question": "pudiera",
    "questionDetails": "Noah Viajaría más si pudiera.",
    "answer": "he could",
    "answerDetails": "Noah would travel more if he could."
  },
  {
    "id": 1353,
    "question": "vimos",
    "questionDetails": "Vimos el amanecer esta mañana.",
    "answer": "we saw, we watched",
    "answerDetails": "We saw the sunrise this morning."
  },
  {
    "id": 1354,
    "question": "tira",
    "questionDetails": "Abróchate las tiras de tus zapatos o te tropezarás en los adoquines.",
    "answer": "strap",
    "answerDetails": "Fasten the straps on your shoes or you’ll trip on the cobblestones."
  },
  {
    "id": 1355,
    "question": "embargo",
    "questionDetails": "Finalmente, levantó el embargo sobre la gelatina.",
    "answer": "embargo, lien, seizure",
    "answerDetails": "Then it lifted the embargo on gelatine."
  },
  {
    "id": 1356,
    "question": "caminar",
    "questionDetails": "Caminar regularmente es bueno para la salud cardiovascular.",
    "answer": "walking",
    "answerDetails": "Walking regularly is good for cardiovascular health."
  },
  {
    "id": 1357,
    "question": "despierta",
    "questionDetails": "La gente dice que despierta tan renovada.",
    "answer": "wake up, awake, wakes",
    "answerDetails": "People say they wake up so refreshed."
  },
  {
    "id": 1358,
    "question": "campo",
    "questionDetails": "En el escudo de armas de nuestra familia aparece una flor de lis sobre un campo azul celeste.",
    "answer": "field, course, countryside",
    "answerDetails": "Our family coat of arms shows a fleur-de-lis on a field of Azure blue."
  },
  {
    "id": 1359,
    "question": "intentando",
    "questionDetails": "Todo este tiempo han estado intentando mostrarnos algo.",
    "answer": "trying, tryingto, attempting",
    "answerDetails": "All this time have been trying show us something."
  },
  {
    "id": 1360,
    "question": "empecé",
    "questionDetails": "Empecé de ama de llaves en un hotel.",
    "answer": "started, began",
    "answerDetails": "Started by housekeeping in a hotel."
  },
  {
    "id": 1361,
    "question": "barrio",
    "questionDetails": "Construyeron el barrio sobre puro campo.",
    "answer": "neighbourhood, quarter",
    "answerDetails": "The neighbourhood was built in open countryside."
  },
  {
    "id": 1362,
    "question": "preocupa",
    "questionDetails": "Todo eso me preocupa.",
    "answer": "worries, ‘m worried about, worried",
    "answerDetails": "It all just worries me."
  },
  {
    "id": 1363,
    "question": "muchísimas",
    "questionDetails": "Has entrevistado a muchísimas mujeres para este libro.",
    "answer": "many",
    "answerDetails": "You have interviewed many, many women for this book."
  },
  {
    "id": 1364,
    "question": "opinión",
    "questionDetails": "Mi opinión es que siempre se debe dar por lo menos 15 por ciento de propina.",
    "answer": "view, say, opinion",
    "answerDetails": "My view is that you should always tip at least 15 percent."
  },
  {
    "id": 1365,
    "question": "vean",
    "questionDetails": "Vean si tiene pulso femoral.",
    "answer": "see",
    "answerDetails": "See if you can get a femoral pulse."
  },
  {
    "id": 1366,
    "question": "aviso",
    "questionDetails": "Los bomberos les dieron un aviso a los vecinos para que se marcharan de sus pisos.",
    "answer": "warning",
    "answerDetails": "The fire department gave the neighbors a warning to leave their apartments."
  },
  {
    "id": 1367,
    "question": "consejo",
    "questionDetails": "Una prohibición de los autobuses escolares que utilizan la carretera fue impuesta por el Consejo del Condado.",
    "answer": "council, board, advice",
    "answerDetails": "A ban on school buses using the road was imposed by the County Council."
  },
  {
    "id": 1368,
    "question": "mueve",
    "questionDetails": "Venga, mueve la mano.",
    "answer": "move, shake, drives",
    "answerDetails": "Now then, move your hand."
  },
  {
    "id": 1369,
    "question": "tomo",
    "questionDetails": "… había reunido los conocimientos de este reino en un tomo.",
    "answer": "tome, take, volume",
    "answerDetails": "… knowledge of the fantastical realm been assembled in one tome."
  },
  {
    "id": 1370,
    "question": "izquierda",
    "questionDetails": "Siempre he dicho que las opiniones de ese periodista son muy de la Izquierda.",
    "answer": "left",
    "answerDetails": "I have always said that that reporter’s views are far to the left."
  },
  {
    "id": 1371,
    "question": "romper",
    "questionDetails": "Tenga cuidado de no romper el vidrio.",
    "answer": "crack",
    "answerDetails": "Take care not to crack the glass."
  },
  {
    "id": 1372,
    "question": "alrededor",
    "questionDetails": "Irá alrededor del perímetro.",
    "answer": "around",
    "answerDetails": "This will go all around the perimeter."
  },
  {
    "id": 1373,
    "question": "especie",
    "questionDetails": "Un mazo es una especie de martillo.",
    "answer": "kind, sort",
    "answerDetails": "A Mallet is a kind of hammer."
  },
  {
    "id": 1374,
    "question": "permitir",
    "questionDetails": "Este software permitirá un tiempo de respuesta más rápido.",
    "answer": "enable",
    "answerDetails": "This software will enable quicker response times."
  },
  {
    "id": 1375,
    "question": "fíjate",
    "questionDetails": "Fíjate en el servicio.",
    "answer": "look",
    "answerDetails": "Look at the service."
  },
  {
    "id": 1376,
    "question": "disculpa",
    "questionDetails": "Me dio una disculpa por haber llegado tarde.",
    "answer": "excuse, apology",
    "answerDetails": "He gave me an excuse for arriving late."
  },
  {
    "id": 1377,
    "question": "bar",
    "questionDetails": "Yo nunca hago eso, ir a un bar solo.",
    "answer": "bar, pub, snack bar",
    "answerDetails": "I never do that, go to a bar alone."
  },
  {
    "id": 1378,
    "question": "recuperar",
    "questionDetails": "Me enviaron a recuperar las pelotas de su jardín.",
    "answer": "retrieve, regain",
    "answerDetails": "I was sent to retrieve the balls from his garden."
  },
  {
    "id": 1379,
    "question": "estudiar",
    "questionDetails": "Se inclinó la cabeza para estudiar los planes.",
    "answer": "study",
    "answerDetails": "She bent her head to study the plans."
  },
  {
    "id": 1380,
    "question": "mantener",
    "questionDetails": "Todo lo que podía mantener abajo era el agua.",
    "answer": "keep, maintain, hold",
    "answerDetails": "All I could keep down was water."
  },
  {
    "id": 1381,
    "question": "compromiso",
    "questionDetails": "Gracias por la invitación, pero tengo un compromiso previo.",
    "answer": "commitment, engagement, compromise",
    "answerDetails": "Thanks for the invitation, but I have a prior commitment."
  },
  {
    "id": 1382,
    "question": "clases",
    "questionDetails": "A algunos padres les parece injusto que no todos los estudiantes reciban clases extraescolares, porque se pueden quedar rezagados.",
    "answer": "coaching",
    "answerDetails": "Some parents feel that it’s unfair that not all students receive extracurricular coaching, because they can fall behind."
  },
  {
    "id": 1383,
    "question": "pareció",
    "answer": "Found"
  },
  {
    "id": 1384,
    "question": "alguno",
    "questionDetails": "¿Hay alguno de los nuevos videos disponibles?",
    "answer": "any",
    "answerDetails": "Are any of the new videos available?"
  },
  {
    "id": 1385,
    "question": "español",
    "answer": "Spaniard"
  },
  {
    "id": 1386,
    "question": "irte",
    "questionDetails": "Quizá quieras irte a casa y tomar un baño.",
    "answer": "go, leave, walk away",
    "answerDetails": "You should probably just go home and draw a bath."
  },
  {
    "id": 1387,
    "question": "gustado",
    "questionDetails": "Me gusta haberte gustado.",
    "answer": "liked",
    "answerDetails": "I like that you liked me."
  },
  {
    "id": 1388,
    "question": "creía",
    "questionDetails": "Hobbes fue un filósofo inglés. Creía que la religión debía estar divorciada de la política.",
    "answer": "he believed",
    "answerDetails": "Hobbes was an English philosopher. He believed that religion should be divorced from politics."
  },
  {
    "id": 1389,
    "question": "amigas",
    "questionDetails": "¿Dónde está mamá?-Salió con sus amigas.",
    "answer": "girls",
    "answerDetails": "Where’s Mom?-She went out with the girls."
  },
  {
    "id": 1390,
    "question": "obvio",
    "questionDetails": "Era obvio que una tormenta venía en.",
    "answer": "obvious",
    "answerDetails": "It was obvious a storm was coming in."
  },
  {
    "id": 1391,
    "question": "partido",
    "questionDetails": "Punto M de partido.",
    "answer": "match, party, game",
    "answerDetails": "Match point."
  },
  {
    "id": 1392,
    "question": "guardia",
    "questionDetails": "Trabajo como guardia de seguridad en un centro comercial.",
    "answer": "guard, duty",
    "answerDetails": "I work as a security guard at a mall."
  },
  {
    "id": 1393,
    "question": "listos",
    "questionDetails": "Ya están casi listos para la lucha.",
    "answer": "ready, smart, clever",
    "answerDetails": "Now they are almost ready for the clash."
  },
  {
    "id": 1394,
    "question": "banco",
    "questionDetails": "El banco nos concedió una hipoteca a un tipo de interés bajo.",
    "answer": "bank, bench",
    "answerDetails": "The bank gave us a mortgage at a low interest rate."
  },
  {
    "id": 1395,
    "question": "vengas",
    "questionDetails": "Necesito que vengas a la boda.",
    "answer": "come",
    "answerDetails": "I just want you to come to the wedding."
  },
  {
    "id": 1396,
    "question": "necesitar",
    "questionDetails": "Esperaba que pudieras necesitar transporte.",
    "answer": "need",
    "answerDetails": "I was hoping you might need a ride."
  },
  {
    "id": 1397,
    "question": "sacó",
    "questionDetails": "Quiero decir, que sacó gente conmigo.",
    "answer": "pulled, drew",
    "answerDetails": "I mean, he pulled bodies with me."
  },
  {
    "id": 1398,
    "question": "preciosa",
    "questionDetails": "Preciosa confunde inercia con romance.",
    "answer": "precious, beautiful, lovely",
    "answerDetails": "Precious has inertia confused with romance."
  },
  {
    "id": 1399,
    "question": "faltaba",
    "questionDetails": "Lo que nos faltaba era una interfaz centralizada.",
    "answer": "lacked, missing",
    "answerDetails": "What we lacked was a centralized interface."
  },
  {
    "id": 1400,
    "question": "cansado",
    "questionDetails": "Fisher se frotó los ojos cansados.",
    "answer": "tired, weary",
    "answerDetails": "Fisher rubbed his tired eyes."
  }
]